[
  {
    "front": "Hello. (formal) ",
    "back": "Salve. (sAH-lveh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Hello. (informal) ",
    "back": "Ciao. (chow)"
  },
  {
    "front": "How are you? (informal)",
    "back": "Come stai? (koh-meh STAI?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "How are you? (formal)",
    "back": "Come sta? (koh-meh STAH?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Fine, thank you. ",
    "back": "Bene, grazie. (BEH-neh, GRAHT-tsyeh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "What is your name? (informal)",
    "back": "Come ti chiami? (KOH-meh tee kee-AH-mee?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "What is your name? (formal)",
    "back": "Come si chiama? (KOH-meh see kee-AH-mah?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "My name is ______ . ",
    "back": "Mi chiamo ______ . (mee kee-AH-moh _____)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Nice to meet you. ",
    "back": "Piacere di conoscerla. (pyah-CHEH-reh dee koh-noh-SHEHR-lah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Please. ",
    "back": "Per favore. (PEHR fah-VOH-reh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Thank you. ",
    "back": "Grazie. (GRAHT-tsyeh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "You're welcome. ",
    "back": "Prego. (PREH-goh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "No problem. ",
    "back": "Non c'è problema (non cheh proh-BLEH-mah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Yes ",
    "back": "Sì. (SEE)"
  },
  {
    "front": "No ",
    "back": "No. (noh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Excuse me (formal)",
    "back": "Mi scusi. (mee SKOO-zee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Excuse me (informal)",
    "back": "Scusa (SKOO-sah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "What's that? ",
    "back": "Che cos'è? (KAY kohz-ay)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I'm sorry. ",
    "back": "Mi dispiace. (mee dee-SPYA-chee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Goodbye. (informal) ",
    "back": "Ciao. (\"chow\")"
  },
  {
    "front": "Goodbye. (formal) ",
    "back": "Arrivederci. (ahr-ree-veh-DEHR-chee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "See you.  ",
    "back": "Ci vediamo. (chee veh-DYAH-moh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Sure. ",
    "back": "Certamente (cher-TAH-men-teh)or Certo (CHEHR-toh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Really? ",
    "back": "Davvero? (dahv-VEH-roh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I don't speak Italian. ",
    "back": "Non parlo italiano. (non PAHR-loh ee-TAH-lyah-noh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Do you speak English? (formal)",
    "back": "Parla inglese? (PAHR-lah een-GLEH-zeh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Do you speak English? (informal)",
    "back": "Parli inglese? (PAHR-lee een-GLEH-zeh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Speak more slowly, please. ",
    "back": "Parli più lentamente/piano, per favore. (PAHR-lee pyoo lehn-TAH-mehn-teh/PYAH-noh, pehr fah-VOH-reh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I understand Italian a little. ",
    "back": "Capisco l’italiano solo un po'. (EE-oh kah-PEES-koh lee-TAH-lyah-noh SOH-loh oon poh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I speak just a few words of Italian.  ",
    "back": "Conosco solo alcune parole in italiano. (koh-NOHS-koh SOH-loh ahl-KOO-neh pah-ROH-leh een ee-TAH-lyah-noh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Is there someone here who speaks English? ",
    "back": "Qualcuno parla inglese? (kwahl-KOO-noh PAHR-lah een-GLEH-zeh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "What does it mean? ",
    "back": "Che cosa significa? (keh KOH-zah see-NYEE-fee-kah?)or Che cosa vuol dire? (keh KOH-zah vwohl DEE-reh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I forgot. ",
    "back": "Mi sono dimenticato. (Mee SOH-noh dee-MEHN-tee-kah-toh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Now I remember. ",
    "back": "Ora ricordo. (OH-rah ree-KOHR-doh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I don’t know.",
    "back": "Non lo so. (nohn loh soh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "After ",
    "back": "Dopo (DOH-poh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Before ",
    "back": "Prima (PREE-mah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Wait! ",
    "back": "Aspetta! (ahs-PEHT-tah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I have a question.  ",
    "back": "Ho una domanda. (oh OO-nah doh-MAHN-dah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Can you tell me...  ",
    "back": "Lei può dirmi... (lay pwoh DEER-mee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "How to get to...  ",
    "back": "Come arrivare a... (KOH-meh ahr-REE-vah-reh ah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Where/When do we meet? ",
    "back": "Dove/Quando ci incontriamo? (DOH-veh/ KWAHN-doh chee een-KOHN-tryah-moh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "How is the weather? ",
    "back": "Che tempo fa? (keh TEHM-poh fah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "While ",
    "back": "Mentre (MEHN-treh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "So ",
    "back": "Così (koh-ZEE)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Why/Because ",
    "back": "Perché (pehr-KEH)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Pardon?  ",
    "back": "Come? (KOH-meh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Help! ",
    "back": "Aiuto! (ah-YOO-toh!)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Good morning. ",
    "back": "Buon giorno. (bwohn JOHR-noh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Good afternoon. ",
    "back": "Buon pomeriggio. (bwohn poh-meh-REE-joh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Good evening. ",
    "back": "Buona sera. (bwoh-nah-SEH-rah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Good night. ",
    "back": "Buona notte. (bwoh-nah-NOHT-teh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I don't understand. ",
    "back": "Non capisco. (nohn kah-PEES-koh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Where are the restrooms? (public place) ",
    "back": "Dove sono i gabinetti? (doh-VEH SOH-noh ee gah-bee-NEHT-tee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Where is the bathroom? (someone's home) ",
    "back": "Dov'è il bagno? (doh-VEH eel BAHN-yoh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Leave me alone. ",
    "back": "Mi lasci in pace (mee LAH-shee IN PAH-cheh)or Lasciami in paceor Mi lasci stare (mee LAH-shee STAH-reh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Don't touch me! ",
    "back": "Non mi toccare! (NOHN mee TOH-kare!)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I'll call the police. ",
    "back": "Chiamo la polizia. (KYAH-moh lah poh-LEE-tsyah!)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Police! ",
    "back": "Polizia! (poh-LEE-tsyah!)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Stop! Thief! ",
    "back": "Al ladro! (ahl LAH-droh!)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I need your help. ",
    "back": "Ho bisogno del tuo aiuto. (oh bee-ZOH-nyoh dehl too-oh ah-YOO-toh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "It's an emergency. ",
    "back": "È un'emergenza. (eh oo-neh-mehr-JEN-tsah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I'm lost. ",
    "back": "Mi sono perso/a. (mee soh-noh PEHR-soh/sah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I lost my bag. ",
    "back": "Ho perso la mia borsa. (oh PEHR-soh lah MEE-ah BOHR-sah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I lost my wallet. ",
    "back": "Ho perso il mio portafoglio. (oh PEHR-soh eel myoh pohr-tah-FOH-lyoh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I'm sick. ",
    "back": "Sono malato/a. (SOH-noh mah-LAH-toh/tah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I've been injured. ",
    "back": "Mi sono ferito/a. (mee SOH-noh feh-REE-toh/tah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I need a doctor. ",
    "back": "Ho bisogno di un medico. (oh bee-ZOH-nyoh dee oon meh-DEE-coh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Can I use your phone? ",
    "back": "Posso usare il suo telefono? (POS-soh oo-ZAH-reh eel swoh teh-LEH-foh-noh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "1 ",
    "back": "uno (OO-noh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "2 ",
    "back": "due (DOO-eh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "3 ",
    "back": "tre (treh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "4 ",
    "back": "quattro (KWAH-troh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "5 ",
    "back": "cinque (CHEEN-kweh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "6 ",
    "back": "sei (SEH-ee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "7 ",
    "back": "sette (SEH-teh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "8 ",
    "back": "otto (OH-toh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "9 ",
    "back": "nove (NOH-veh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "10 ",
    "back": "dieci (DYEH-chee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "11 ",
    "back": "undici (OON-dee-chee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "12 ",
    "back": "dodici (DOH-dee-chee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "13 ",
    "back": "tredici (TREH-dee-chee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "14 ",
    "back": "quattordici (kwahr-TOHR-dee-chee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "15 ",
    "back": "quindici (KWEEN-dee-chee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "16 ",
    "back": "sedici (SEH-dee-chee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "17 ",
    "back": "diciassette (dee-chee-ah-SSEH-teh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "18 ",
    "back": "diciotto (dee-CHOH-toh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "19 ",
    "back": "diciannove (dee-chah-NOH-veh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "20 ",
    "back": "venti (VEHN-tee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "21 ",
    "back": "ventuno (vehn-TOO-noh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "22 ",
    "back": "ventidue (vehn-tee-DOO-eh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "23 ",
    "back": "ventitré (vehn-tee-TREH)"
  },
  {
    "front": "30 ",
    "back": "trenta (TREHN-tah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "40 ",
    "back": "quaranta (kwah-RAHN-tah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "50 ",
    "back": "cinquanta (cheen-KWAHN-tah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "60 ",
    "back": "sessanta (sehs-SAHN-tah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "70 ",
    "back": "settanta (seht-TAHN-tah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "80 ",
    "back": "ottanta (oht-TAHN-tah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "90 ",
    "back": "novanta (noh-VAHN-tah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "100 ",
    "back": "cento (CHEHN-toh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "200 ",
    "back": "duecento (dweh-CHEHN-toh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "300 ",
    "back": "trecento (treh-CHEHN-toh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "1,000 ",
    "back": "mille (MEEL-leh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "2,000 ",
    "back": "duemila (dweh-MEE-lah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "1,000,000 ",
    "back": "un milione (oon mee-LYOH-neh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "1,000,000,000 ",
    "back": "un miliardo (oo mee-LYAHR-doh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "1,000,000,000,000 ",
    "back": "mille miliardi (MEEL-leh mee-LYAHR-dee) or un bilione (oo bee-LYOH-neh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "number _____ (train, bus, etc.) ",
    "back": "numero_____ (NOO-meh-roh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "half ",
    "back": "mezzo (MEHD-dzoh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "less ",
    "back": "meno (MEH-noh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "more ",
    "back": "più (pyoo)"
  },
  {
    "front": "now ",
    "back": "adesso (ah-DEHSS-oh) - ora"
  },
  {
    "front": "later ",
    "back": "più tardi (PYOO-TAR-dee) - dopo (\"DOH-poh\")"
  },
  {
    "front": "before ",
    "back": "prima (PREE-ma)"
  },
  {
    "front": "morning ",
    "back": "mattino (mah-TEEN-oh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "afternoon ",
    "back": "pomeriggio (poh-meh-REED-joh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "evening ",
    "back": "sera (SEH-rah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "night ",
    "back": "notte (NOHT-teh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "one o'clock AM ",
    "back": "l'una (LOO-nah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "two o'clock AM ",
    "back": "le due (leh DOO-eh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "noon ",
    "back": "mezzogiorno (mehd-dzoh-JOHR-noh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "one o'clock PM ",
    "back": "le tredici (leh TREH-dee-chee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "two o'clock PM ",
    "back": "le quattordici (leh kwaht-TOHR-dee-chee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "midnight ",
    "back": "mezzanotte (mehd-dzah-NOHT-teh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "_____ minute(s) ",
    "back": "_____ minuto/ti (mee-NOO-toh/tee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "_____ hour(s) ",
    "back": "_____ ora/e (OH-rah/eh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "_____ day(s) ",
    "back": "_____ giorno/ni (JOHR-noh/nee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "_____ week(s) ",
    "back": "_____ settimana/ne (seht-tee-MAH-nah/neh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "_____ month(s) ",
    "back": "_____ mese/si (MEH-zeh/zee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "_____ year(s) ",
    "back": "_____ anno/ni (AHN-noh/nee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "today ",
    "back": "oggi (OHD-jee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "yesterday ",
    "back": "ieri (YEH-ree)"
  },
  {
    "front": "tomorrow ",
    "back": "domani (doh-MAH-nee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "day after tomorrow ",
    "back": "dopo domani ( doh-poh doh-MAH-nee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "this week ",
    "back": "questa settimana (KWEHS-tah seht-tee-MAH-nah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "last week ",
    "back": "la settimana scorsa (lah set-tee-MAH-nah SKOR-sah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "next week ",
    "back": "la prossima settimana (lah PROHS-see-mah set-tee-MAH-nah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Sunday ",
    "back": "domenica (doh-MEH-nee-kah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Monday ",
    "back": "lunedì (loo-neh-DEE)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Tuesday ",
    "back": "martedì (mahr-teh-DEE)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Wednesday ",
    "back": "mercoledì (mehr-koh-leh-DEE)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Thursday ",
    "back": "giovedì (joh-veh-DEE)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Friday ",
    "back": "venerdì (veh-nehr-DEE)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Saturday ",
    "back": "sabato (SAH-bah-toh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "January ",
    "back": "gennaio (jehn-NAH-yoh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "February ",
    "back": "febbraio (fehb-BRAH-yoh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "March ",
    "back": "marzo (MAR-tso)"
  },
  {
    "front": "April ",
    "back": "aprile (ah-PREE-leh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "May ",
    "back": "maggio (MAHD-joh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "June ",
    "back": "giugno (JOO-nyoh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "July ",
    "back": "luglio (LOO-lyoh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "August ",
    "back": "agosto (ah-GOHS-toh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "September ",
    "back": "settembre (seht-TEM-breh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "October ",
    "back": "ottobre (oht-TOH-breh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "November ",
    "back": "novembre (noh-VEHM-breh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "December ",
    "back": "dicembre (dee-CHEM-breh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "black ",
    "back": "nero (NEH-roh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "white ",
    "back": "bianco (BYAHN-koh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "gray ",
    "back": "grigio (GREE-joh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "red ",
    "back": "rosso (ROHS-soh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "blue ",
    "back": "blu (bloo)"
  },
  {
    "front": "yellow ",
    "back": "giallo (JAHL-loh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "green ",
    "back": "verde (VEHR-deh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "orange ",
    "back": "arancione (ah-rahn-CHOH-neh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "purple ",
    "back": "viola (VYOH-lah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "brown ",
    "back": "marrone (mahr-ROH-neh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "How much is a ticket to _____? ",
    "back": "Quanto costa un biglietto per _____? (KWAHN-toh KOHS-tah oon bee-LYEHT-toh pehr)"
  },
  {
    "front": "One ticket to _____, please. ",
    "back": "Un biglietto per _____, per favore. (oon bee-LYEHT-toh pehr....pehr fah-VOH-reh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Where does this train/bus go? ",
    "back": "Dove va questo treno / quest'autobus? (DOH-veh vah KWEHS-toh TREH-noh / KWEHS-tow-TOH-boos)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Where is the train/bus to _____? ",
    "back": "Dov'è il treno/l'autobus per _____? (doh-VEH eel TREH-noh/ low-TOH-boos)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Does this train/bus stop in _____? ",
    "back": "Questo treno/quest'autobus si ferma a _____? (KWEHS-toh TREH-noh/ KWEHS-tow-TOH-boos see FEHR-mah ah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "When does the train/bus for _____ leave? ",
    "back": "Quando parte il treno/l'autobus per _____? (KWAHN-doh PAHR-teh eel TREH-noh / low-TOH-boos)"
  },
  {
    "front": "When will this train/bus arrive in _____? ",
    "back": "Quando arriva a _____ questo treno/quest'autobus? (KWAHN-doh ahr-REE-vah ah....KWEHS-toh TREH-noh / KWEHS-tow-TOH-boos)"
  },
  {
    "front": "How do I get to _____ ? ",
    "back": "Come si arriva a _____ ? (Koh-meh see ahr-REE-vah ah...?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...to the railway station? ",
    "back": "...alla stazione ferroviaria? (...ahl-LAH stah-DSYOH-neh fehr-roh-VYAH-ryah?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...to the bus station? ",
    "back": "...alla stazione dell'autobus? (...ahl-LAH stah-DSYOH-neh dehl-LOW-toh-boos?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...to the airport? ",
    "back": "...all'aeroporto? (...ahl-lah-eh-roh-POHR-toh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...downtown? ",
    "back": "...in centro? (...een CHEHN-troh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...the youth hostel? ",
    "back": "...all'ostello? (...ahl-LOHS-tehl-loh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...the small hotel? / hotel? ",
    "back": "...all'albergo? hotel? (...ahl-LAHL-behr-goh/ oh-TEHL?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...the American/Canadian/Australian/British consulate? ",
    "back": "...al consolato Americano/Canadese/Australiano/Inglese? (...ahl kohn-SOH-lah-toh ameh-REE-kah-noh/ kah-nah-DEH-zeh/ ows-trah-LYAH-noh/ ehn-GLEH-zeh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Where are there a lot of... ",
    "back": "Dove ci sono molti... (DOH-veh chee SOH-noh MOHL-tee...)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...hotels? ",
    "back": "...hotel? (...oh-TEH-l?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...restaurants? ",
    "back": "...ristoranti? (...rees-toh-RAHN-tee?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...bars? ",
    "back": "...bar? (bahr?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...sites to see? ",
    "back": "...cose da vedere? (KOH-zeh dah veh-DEH-reh?)or ...luoghi da vedere? (...LOW-gee dah veh-DEH-reh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Can you show (it to) me on the map? ",
    "back": "Potete mostrarmelo sulla carta? (poh-TEH-teh mohs-trahr-MEH-loh sool-LAH KAHR-tah?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "street ",
    "back": "strada (STRAH-dah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Turn left. ",
    "back": "Giri a sinistra. (JEE-ree ah see-NEES-trah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Turn right. ",
    "back": "Giri a destra. (JEE-ree ah DEHS-trah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "left ",
    "back": "sinistra (see-NEES-trah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "right ",
    "back": "destra (DEHS-trah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "straight ahead ",
    "back": "diritto (dee-REET-toh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "towards the _____ ",
    "back": "verso il  _____ (VEHR-zoh eel...)"
  },
  {
    "front": "past the _____ ",
    "back": "dopo il _____ (DOH-poh eel...)"
  },
  {
    "front": "before the _____ ",
    "back": "prima del _____ (PREE-mah dehl...)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Watch for the _____. ",
    "back": "Guarda il _____. (GWAHR-dah eel...)or  Cerca il _____. (CHEHR-kah eel...)"
  },
  {
    "front": "intersection ",
    "back": "incrocio (een-KROH-chyoh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "north ",
    "back": "nord (nohrd)   abbreviation N"
  },
  {
    "front": "south ",
    "back": "sud (sood)   abbreviation S"
  },
  {
    "front": "east ",
    "back": "est (ehst)   abbreviation E"
  },
  {
    "front": "west ",
    "back": "ovest (oh-VEHST)   abbreviation O"
  },
  {
    "front": "Taxi! ",
    "back": "Taxi! (TAHK-see)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Take me to _____, please. ",
    "back": "Portatemi a _____, per favore. (pohr-TAH-teh-mee ah..., pehr fah-VOH-reh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "How much does it cost to get to _____? ",
    "back": "Quanto costa andare a _____? (KWAHN-toh KOHS-tah ahn-DAH-reh ah...?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Please take me to_____. ",
    "back": "Per favore, mi porti a______. (pehr fah-VOH-reh, mee POHR-tee ah...)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I'm in a hurry! ",
    "back": "Vado di fretta! / Ho fretta! (VAH-doh dee FREHT-tah/ oh FREHT-tah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Stop here, please! ",
    "back": "Fermi qui, per favore! (FEHR-mee kwee pehr fah-VOH-reh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "How much do I owe you? ",
    "back": "Quanto Le devo? (KWAHN-toh leh DEH-voh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Do you have any rooms available? ",
    "back": "Avete camere libere? (ah-VEH-teh kah-MEH-reh lee-BEH-reh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "How much is a room for one person/two people? ",
    "back": "Quanto costa una stanza singola/doppia? (KWAHN-toh KOHS-tah OO-nah STAHN-tsah seen-GOH-lah/ DOHP-pyah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Does the room come with... ",
    "back": "La stanza ha ... (lah STAHN-tsah ah...)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...bedsheets? ",
    "back": "...lenzuola? (...lehn-ZWOH-lah?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...a bathroom? ",
    "back": "...un bagno? (...oon BAH-nyoh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...a telephone? ",
    "back": "...un telefono? (...oon teh-LEH-foh-noh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...a TV? ",
    "back": "...un televisore? (...oon teh-leh-VEE-soh-reh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "May I see the room first? ",
    "back": "Posso prima vedere la stanza? (POHS-soh PREE-mah veh-DEH-reh lah STAHN-tsah?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Do you have anything quieter? ",
    "back": "Ha una stanza più silenziosa? (ah OO-nah STAHN-tsah pyoo see-lehn-TSYOH-zah?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...bigger? ",
    "back": "...più grande? (pyoo GRAHN-deh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...cleaner? ",
    "back": "...più pulita? (pyoo poo-LEE-tah?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...cheaper? ",
    "back": "...più economica? (pyoo eh-koh-NOH-mee-kah?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "OK, I'll take it. ",
    "back": "Va bene, la prendo. (vah BEH-neh, lah PREHN-doh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I will stay for _____ night(s). ",
    "back": "Mi fermo per _____ notte(i). (mee FEHR-moh pehr...NOHT-teh(ee))"
  },
  {
    "front": "Can you suggest another hotel? ",
    "back": "Potete suggerirmi un altro hotel? (poh-TEH-teh soo-JEH-reer-mee oon AHL-troh OH-tehl?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Do you have a safe? ",
    "back": "Avete una cassaforte (centrale)? (ah-VEH-teh OO-nah kahs-SAH-fohr-teh (chehn-TRAH-leh)?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Is breakfast/supper included? ",
    "back": "È inclusa la prima colazione / la cena? (EH een-KLOO-zah la PREE-mah koh-lah-TSYOH-neh/ lah CHEH-nah?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "What time is breakfast/supper? ",
    "back": "A che ora è la prima colazione / la cena? (ah keh OH-rah EH lah PREE-mah koh-lah-TSYOH-neh / lah CHEH-nah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Please clean my room. ",
    "back": "Pulite la mia camera, per favore. (poo-LEE-teh lah myah kah-MEH-rah, pehr fah-VOH-reh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Can you wake me at _____? ",
    "back": "Potete svegliarmi alle _____? (poh-TEH-teh sveh-LYAHR-mee AHL-leh....?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I want to check out. ",
    "back": "Voglio andare via. (voh-LYOH ahn-DAH-reh vyah) or voglio partire (voh-LYOH pahr-TEE-reh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Do you accept American/Australian/Canadian dollars? ",
    "back": "Accettate dollari Americani/Australiani/Canadesi? (aht-cheht-TAH-teh DOHL-lah-ree ah-meh-ree-KAH-nee/ ows-trah-LYAH-nee/ kah-nah-DEH-see?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Do you accept British pounds? ",
    "back": "Accettate sterline Inglesi? (aht-cheht-TAH-teh stehr-LEE-neh een-GLEH-zee?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Do you accept credit cards? ",
    "back": "Accettate carte di credito? (aht-cheht-TAH-teh KAHR-teh dee kreh-DEE-toh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Can you change money for me? ",
    "back": "Potete cambiare del denaro per me? (poh-TEH-teh kahm-BYAH-reh dehl deh-NAH-roh pehr meh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Can you change British pounds for me? ",
    "back": "Potete cambiare delle sterline Inglesi per me? (poh-TEH-teh kahm-BYAH-reh DEHL-leh stehr-LEE-neh een-GLEH-zee pehr meh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Can you change American/Australian/Canadian dollars for me? ",
    "back": "Potete cambiare dei dollari Americani/Australiani/Canadesi per me? (poh-TEH-teh kahm-BYAH-reh day DOHL-lah-ree ah-meh-ree-KAH-nee/ ows-trah-LYAH-nee/ kah-nah-DEH-see pehr meh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Where can I get money changed? ",
    "back": "Dove posso cambiare del denaro? (DOH-veh POHS-soh kahm-BYAH-reh dehl deh-NAH-roh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Where can I get foreign money changed? ",
    "back": "Dove posso cambiare della valuta straniera? (DOH-veh POHS-soh kahm-BYAH-reh DEHL-lah vah-LOO-tah strah-NYEH-rah?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Can you change a traveler's check for me? ",
    "back": "Potete cambiare questi traveller's cheque per me? (poh-TEH-teh kahm-BYAH-reh KWEHS-tee TRAH-veh-lehrs checks pehr meh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Where can I get a traveler's check changed? ",
    "back": "Dove posso cambiare un traveller's cheque? (Doh-veh POHS-soh kahm-BYAH-reh oon TRAH-veh-lehrs check?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "What is the exchange rate? ",
    "back": "Quant'è il cambio? (KWAHN-teh eel KAHM-byoh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Where is an automatic teller machine (ATM)? ",
    "back": "Dove posso trovare un Bancomat? (DOH-veh POHS-soh troh-VAH-reh oon bahn-KOH-maht?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "NOTE ",
    "back": "In Italy it is more common to say \"Bancomat\" for \"ATM\""
  },
  {
    "front": "A table for one person/two people, please. ",
    "back": "Un tavolo per uno/due, per favore. (oon tah-VOH-loh pehr OO-noh/ dweh, pehr fah-VOH-reh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Can I look at the menu, please? ",
    "back": "Posso vedere il menu, per favore? (POHS-soh veh-DEH-reh eel meh-NOO, pehr fah-VOH-reh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Is there a house specialty? ",
    "back": "C'è una specialità della casa? (cheh OO-nah speh-chah-lee-TAH DEHL-lah KAH-zah?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Is there a local specialty? ",
    "back": "C'è una specialità locale? (cheh OO-nah speh-chah-lee-TAH loh-KAH-leh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I'm a vegetarian. ",
    "back": "Sono vegetariano/a (SOH-noh veh-jeh-tah-RYAH-noh/ ah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I don't eat pork. ",
    "back": "Non mangio il maiale. (nohn MAHN-joh eel mah-YAH-leh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I don't eat beef. ",
    "back": "Non mangio il manzo. (nohn MAHN-joh eel MAHN-dzoh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I only eat kosher food. ",
    "back": "Mangio solamente cibo kosher. (MAHN-joh soh-LAH-mehn-teh CHEE-boh KOH-shehr)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Can you make it \"lite\", please? (less oil/butter/lard) ",
    "back": "Potete farlo leggero, per favore? (poh-TEH-teh FAHR-loh lehd-JEH-roh, pehr fah-VOH-reh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "fixed-price meal ",
    "back": "or Potete farlo con pochi grassi? (with little fat) (poh-TEH-teh FAHR-loh kohn poh-KHEE GRAHS-see?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "à la carte ",
    "back": "or Potete farlo con poco olio? (with little oil) (poh-TEH-teh FAHR-loh kohn POH-koh OH-lyoh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "breakfast ",
    "back": "pranzo a prezzo fisso (PRAH-tsoh ah PREHD-zoh FEES-soh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "lunch ",
    "back": "à la carte (AH lah KAHR-tah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "tea (meal) ",
    "back": "la prima colazione (lah PREE-mah koh-lah-TSYOH-neh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "supper ",
    "back": "il pranzo (eel PRAHN-dzoh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I would like _____. ",
    "back": "tè (teh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I would like a dish containing _____. ",
    "back": "if you are meaning the meal at the 4 or 5 in the afternoon, in Italian is called  merenda (meh-REHN-dah)  but usually is only for kids"
  },
  {
    "front": "chicken ",
    "back": "la cena (lah CHEH-nah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "beef ",
    "back": "Vorrei  _____. (vohr-RAY)"
  },
  {
    "front": "fish ",
    "back": "Vorrei un piatto con  _____. (vohr-RAY oon PYAHT-toh kohn....)"
  },
  {
    "front": "ham ",
    "back": "il pollo (eel POHL-loh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "sausage ",
    "back": "il manzo (eel MAHN-dzoh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "cheese ",
    "back": "il pesce (eel PEH-sheh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "eggs ",
    "back": "il prosciutto (eel proh-SHOOT-toh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "salad ",
    "back": "salsiccia (sahl-SEET-chah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "(fresh) vegetables ",
    "back": "formaggio (fohr-MAHD-joh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "(fresh) fruit ",
    "back": "uova (WOH-vah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "bread ",
    "back": "insalata (een-sah-LAH-tah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "toast ",
    "back": "verdure fresche (vehr-DOO-reh FREHS-keh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "noodles ",
    "back": "frutta fresca (FROOT-tah FREHS-kah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "rice ",
    "back": "pane (PAH-neh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "beans ",
    "back": "toast (tohst)"
  },
  {
    "front": "May I have a glass of _____? ",
    "back": "tagliatelle (tah-LYAH-tehl-leh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "May I have a cup of _____? ",
    "back": "riso (REE-zoh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "May I have a bottle of _____? ",
    "back": "fagioli (fah-JOH-lee)   or fagiolini (similar to beans but different)"
  },
  {
    "front": "the coffee ",
    "back": "Posso avere un bicchiere di _____? (POHS-soh ah-VEH-reh oon beek-KYEH-reh dee....?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "the tea (drink) ",
    "back": "Posso avere una tazza di _____? (POHS-soh ah-VEH-reh OO-nah TAHT-tsah dee...?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "the juice ",
    "back": "Posso avere una bottiglia di _____? (POHS-soh ah-VEH-reh OO-nah boht-TEE-lyah dee...?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "the water ",
    "back": "il caffè (eel kahf-FEH)"
  },
  {
    "front": "the bubbly water ",
    "back": "il tè (eel TEH)"
  },
  {
    "front": "the beer ",
    "back": "il succo (eel SOOK-koh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "the red/white wine ",
    "back": "l'acqua (LAHK-kwah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "May I have some _____? ",
    "back": "l'acqua frizzante (LAHK-kwah free-DZAHN-teh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "the salt ",
    "back": "la birra (lah beer-RAH)"
  },
  {
    "front": "the black pepper ",
    "back": "il vino rosso/bianco (eel VEE-noh ROHS-soh/ BYAHN-koh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "the butter ",
    "back": "Posso aver del _____? (POHS-soh AH-vehr dehl...?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Excuse me, waiter? (getting attention of server) ",
    "back": "or  Posso avere un po' di ____? (POHS-soh ah-VEH-reh oon POH dee...?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I'm finished. ",
    "back": "il sale (eel SAH-leh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "It was delicious. ",
    "back": "il pepe (eel PEH-peh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Please clear the table. ",
    "back": "il burro (eel BOOR-roh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "The check, please. ",
    "back": "Scusi, cameriere?(m)/cameriera?(f) (SKOO-zee, kah-meh-RYEH-reh?/ kah-meh-RYEH-rah?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Do you serve alcohol? ",
    "back": "Ho finito. (oh fee-NEE-toh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Is there table service? ",
    "back": "È squisito. (EH skwee-ZEE-toh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "A beer/two beers, please. ",
    "back": "Potete pulire il tavolo, per favore. (poh-TEH-teh poo-LEE-reh eel tah-VOH-loh, pehr fah-VOH-reh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "A glass of red/white wine, please. ",
    "back": "Il conto, per favore. (eel KOHN-toh, pehr fah-VOH-reh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "A pint, please. ",
    "back": "Avete bevande alcoliche? (ah-VEH-teh beh-VAHN-deh ahl-KOH-lee-keh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "A bottle, please. ",
    "back": "C'è il servizio al tavolo? (cheh eel sehr-VEE-zyoh ahl tah-VOH-loh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I'd like a_______? ",
    "back": "Una birra/due birre, per favore. (OO-nah BEER-rah/ dweh BEER-reh, pehr fah-VOH-reh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "beer ",
    "back": "Un bicchiere di vino rosso/bianco, per favore. (oon beek-KYEH-reh dee VEE-noh ROHS-soh/ BYAHN-koh, pehr fah-VOH-reh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "wine ",
    "back": "Un boccale, per favore. (oon bohk-KAH-leh, pehr fah-VOH-reh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "gin ",
    "back": "Una bottiglia, per favore. (OO-nah boht-TEE-lyah, pehr fah-VOH-reh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "whiskey ",
    "back": "Vorrei un_____? (vohr-RAY oon...?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "vodka ",
    "back": "birra (BEER-rah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "rum ",
    "back": "vino (VEE-noh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "water ",
    "back": "gin (jeen)"
  },
  {
    "front": "club soda ",
    "back": "whisky (WEES-kee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "tonic water ",
    "back": "vodka (VOHD-kah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "orange juice ",
    "back": "rum (rohm)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Coke (soda) ",
    "back": "acqua (AHK-kwah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "A soda. ",
    "back": "club soda (kloob SOH-dah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Do you have any bar snacks? ",
    "back": "acqua tonica (AHK-kwah toh-NEE-kah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "One more, please. ",
    "back": "succo di arancia (SOOK-koh dee ah-RAHN-chah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Another round, please. ",
    "back": "Coca Cola (KOH-kah KOH-lah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "When is closing time? ",
    "back": "Una soda. (OO-nah SOH-dah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Do you have this in my size? ",
    "back": "Avete qualcosa da stuzzicare? (a-VE-te kwalcoza da STU-zee-ca-ray?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "How much is this? ",
    "back": "Un altro, per favore. (oon AHL-troh, pehr fah-VOH-reh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "That's too expensive. ",
    "back": "Un altro giro, per favore. (oon AHL-troh JEE-roh, pehr fah-VOH-reh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Would you take _____? ",
    "back": "Qual è l'ora di chiusura? (kwah-LEH loh-RAH dee KYOO-zoo-rah?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "expensive ",
    "back": "Avete questo nella mia taglia? (ah-VEH-teh KWEHS-toh NEHL-lah myah tah-LYAH?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "cheap ",
    "back": "Quanto costa questo? (KWAHN-toh KOHS-tah KWEHS-toh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I can't afford it. ",
    "back": "È troppo caro/a. (EH TROHP-poh KAH-roh/ah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I am looking for something cheaper. ",
    "back": "Prendereste _____? (prehn-DEH-rehs-teh....?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I don't want it. ",
    "back": "caro (KAH-roh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "You're cheating me. ",
    "back": "economico (eh-koh-NOH-mee-koh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I'm not interested. ",
    "back": "Non posso permettermelo. (nohn POHS-soh pehr-meht-TEHR-meh-loh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "OK, I'll take it. ",
    "back": "Cerco qualcosa di più; economico. (CHEHR-koh KWAHL-koh-zah dee pyoo eh-koh-NOH-mee-koh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Can I have a bag? ",
    "back": "Non lo voglio. (nohn loh voh-LYOH)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Do you ship (overseas)? ",
    "back": "Mi state imbrogliando. (mee STAH-teh eem-broh-LYAHN-doh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I need... ",
    "back": "Non son interessato. (nohn sohn een-teh-REHS-sah-toh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...toothpaste. ",
    "back": "Va bene, lo prendo. (vah BEH-neh, loh PREHN-doh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...toothbrush. ",
    "back": "Posso avere una busta? (POHS-soh AVEH-reh OO-nah BOOS-tah?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...tampons. ",
    "back": "Potete spedirlo (all'estero)? (poh-TEH-teh speh-DEER-loh (AHL-lehs-TEH-roh)?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...soap. ",
    "back": "Ho bisogno di... (oh bee-SOH-byoh dee...)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...shampoo. ",
    "back": "...dentifricio. (dehn-tee-FREE-choh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...pain reliever. ",
    "back": "...spazzolino da denti. (spaht-tsoh-LEE-noh dah DEHN-tee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...cold medicine. ",
    "back": "...tampone/assorbente. (tahm-POH-neh/ ahs-SOHR-behn-teh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...stomach medicine. ",
    "back": "...sapone. (sah-POH-neh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...a razor. ",
    "back": "...shampoo. (SHAHM-poo)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...an umbrella. ",
    "back": "...aspirina. (ahs-pee-REE-nah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...sunblock lotion. ",
    "back": "...medicina per il raffreddore. (meh-dee-CHEE-nah pehr eel rahf-FREHD-doh-reh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...a postcard. ",
    "back": "...medicina per lo stomaco. (meh-dee-CHEE-nah pehr loh stoh-MAH-koh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...postage stamps. ",
    "back": "...un rasoio. (oon rah-ZOH-io)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...batteries. ",
    "back": "...un ombrello. (oon ohm-BREHL-loh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...writing paper. ",
    "back": "...lozione/crema solare. (loh-TSYOH-neh/ KREH-mah soh-LAH-reh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...a pen. ",
    "back": "...una cartolina. (OO-nah kahr-TOH-lee-nah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...a pencil. ",
    "back": "...francobolli. (frahn-koh-BOHL-lee)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...English-language books. ",
    "back": "...batterie. (baht-TEH-ryeh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...English-language magazines. ",
    "back": "...carta. (KAHR-tah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...an English-language newspaper. ",
    "back": "...una penna. (OO-nah PEHN-nah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "...an English-Italian dictionary. ",
    "back": "...una matita. (OO-nah mah-TEE-tah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I want to rent a car. ",
    "back": "...libri in inglese. (LEE-bree een een-GLEH-zeh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Can I get insurance? ",
    "back": "...riviste in inglese. (ree-VEES-teh een een-GLEH-zeh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "stop (on a street sign) ",
    "back": "...un giornale in inglese. (oon johr-NAH-leh een een-GLEH-zeh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "one way ",
    "back": "...un dizionario Inglese-Italiano. (oon dee-tsyoh-NAH-ryoh een-GLEH-zeh-ee-tah-LYAH-noh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "yield ",
    "back": "Desidero noleggiare una macchina. (deh-SEE-deh-roh noh-lehd-JAH-reh OO-nah mahk-KEE-nah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "no entry ",
    "back": "or Vorrei noleggiare una macchina (vohr-REY noh-lehd-JAH-reh OO-nah mahk-KEY-nah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "no parking ",
    "back": "Posso avere un'assicurazione? (POHS-soh ah-VEH-reh oo-nahs-see-koo-RAH-tsyoh-neh?)"
  },
  {
    "front": "speed limit ",
    "back": "stop (stohp)"
  },
  {
    "front": "gas (petrol) station ",
    "back": "senso unico (SEHN-soh OO-nee-koh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "petrol ",
    "back": "dare la precedenza (DAH-leh lah preh-cheh-DEHN-tsah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "diesel ",
    "back": "divieto di accesso (dee-VYEH-toh dee aht-CHEHS-soh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I haven't done anything wrong. ",
    "back": "sosta vietata  (SOHS-tah vyeh-TAH-tah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "It was a misunderstanding. ",
    "back": "or vietato parcheggiare (vyeh-TAH-toh pahr-kehd-JAH-reh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Where are you taking me? ",
    "back": "limite di velocità; (lee-MEE-teh dee veh-loh-chee-TAH)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Am I under arrest? ",
    "back": "benzinaio (behn-dzee-NAH-yoh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I am an American/Australian/British/Canadian citizen. ",
    "back": "or stazione di rifornimento (stah-TSYOH-neh dee ree-fohr-NEE-mehn-toh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I want to talk to the American/Australian/British/Canadian embassy/consulate. ",
    "back": "or (in an highway) area di servizio (AH-reh-ah dee sehr-VEE-tsyoh)"
  },
  {
    "front": "I want to talk to a lawyer. ",
    "back": "benzina (only unleaded one) (behn-DZEE-nah)"
  },
  {
    "front": "Can I just pay a fine now? ",
    "back": "diesel (DEE-zehl)"
  }
]
